Hello, welcome to the next episode of Learn German in Hindi. Till now, in the
middle of the episodes, we have covered all the
concepts of and, they have also covered some concepts of *. Actually,
because the
concepts of simple past tense, Chief Minister,
some people also consider them in two, then
we have already learnt them in almost 2030, so today when we are doing this and and,
today we are going to learn what is the
exam format of and and
we are going to show some tips for it today,
so how are we going to see it,
first of all we will see what is this 182 B1
B2, after that when we are going to see what is the format of oral exam,
after that we are going to see what is the format of specific A2 intake
and we will see its four parts, after that
we will see how to give this exam
and in the end I will give you some
tips so that you can do it in a good way,
and now the second thing is that
if you have any doubts in this, then
you can tell me about it.  You can write this Winslet in this comment box.
I am going to come live at India timing 09:38 PM. If you have
any doubt then I will discuss it there. Let's
start with
182 B1 B2 C 132. It is a
simple thing for everyone. Now the one who knows how to
speak, my name is Kirdar, he
says that I know English and the one who has done
PhD in English also says that I know English. So
how will you decide
what kind of English you know?
What did the European Commission do for that?
They have created a framework, apk
file, what does it mean? They have created a Common European Framework
of Reference. What will happen with that is that for
how much you know any of your languages,
you are given a record length for that. It has been divided into
6 parts. 182 B1 B2 C Vanshi 272
means what does it mean? B1 B2 means intermediate,
C1 and C2 means proficient. So
if you are fluent in any language, then you know a
specific skill set. So, if you are fluent in that language, then
you have to introduce yourself.  They know how to give, they know how to
ask small questions, they know how to make
small requests and if the person in
front of them is ready to talk to you calmly then
you can communicate with him whether
he is from this branch or from Germany or from
Britain,
what does beaver mean is that now you can
comment a little better and
can give your opinion and if you are smart and
proficient then it means that you can
say anything to him at any speed, he will be able to complete it for you, so
what is there to think about in this that is there no such thing anywhere in the country, is there
so much grammar off, then
you are seven or he or situ, it is
500 or 1000 for you, so both of you are both, it is all
different that how much you
understand the language, see how hard it is in German, it is
not that hard in English, the
continuous tense in English is not that hard in German,
so you cannot do it like that, if you know
continuous tense then you have to
remember this thing  There is a 182, they measure your
language proficiency level and
not your grammar or k, but it is
easier to teach, that is
why all teachers divide grammar a little,
okay, now this opinion is that it is
okay, so the institute is a
funded organization of the German government,
it is International Acclaim, it has
more than one hundred and fifty offices in many countries
and it works in spreading the German language and German culture,
I myself had reached Sevan, I
studied from the institute and I am a
big fan of it because they do
not just teach the language, it is about
life and culture of Germany
and these are all international scientific institutes,
they also have the right to give it, it was only one, so
you can also do their courses
or you want to take extra by setting up your own cells, you
can give glimpses to any level, that
border, come here right now and I want to know 12 more that you can
take immediately, but carefully, the
most important thing is that the maximum should come out,
hence we will talk about the voice so much, so now
we have come to know that this is no  Now what is this thing,
but what is its exam pattern,
so this is very interesting
friends, till now they were told that it is an
English exam, so what do you mean by that,
bring Monday's paper, how is your spelling,
everything is different on that, now if you see, at some places there is
also an oral exam of a few twenty marks, read naturally, you have to
write, so the language comes, it is
not like that here, how is it in CA firms here in
Dubai, what are the four skills,
Pareshan means speaking,
Shravan means writing, Yauvan means listening and
Laser means reading, all these four skills have 20%
equal weightage, then if you go to Inch or Situ
and even if you go to Situ, then also the same will change, the
format of the exam will change a little, that
Baba, how many marks will we change, passing
etc. will change, then it will always remain the same
that all these four will have 20% marks, clear to
everyone, now let us see the format of the And, so
as we told them,
they have 25 marks per four skills,
here all the four skills are there  15 Marg
were for Special 1556 15 Lizam 15 and this is
what is the total amount for us, hit sixty, right now
these six markets are only for
and what happens only till the level, what does it
mean, together 60 per
cent means 36 for you, then you have passed, that
means there is no need to do it for the 9th time in heart school,
for Satya Roti you get 15
15 960, even then you have passed, there is nothing to be afraid,
I myself have 98% in this, I have seen so
many students with marks above 90% in this, up
to hundred percent are ill,
just one thing should be clear that the time is passing there,
passing happens together, that is why I have given you this
example, so it
is simple, four parts in each 15 15
15 15 Marg, so now we will see every point in detail, first of all
what is the problem, that is to
say it is very simple, so first of all what happens is that
you have to do it in your introduction itself,
for that you should have done this  If it is
good then there is no need to look at the paper, you have
given your introduction that this is
my character, I come from here, I
live here, I am an engineer, whatever
you know this year,
one mark for saying the same, then they will
ask for sparing on what you said, mode start means
character, so eat half wire character is only one
and one number, nothing, tell me your telephone
number, tell me your pin code number,
it was one, it was hit, how simple,
so what happens in the next lesson, what happens in the next part is
question and answer, so what happens is
you are given a team, if you see
this device, it means food and drink, I and
world are done, broad means red, so
make whatever you want from it, that
word is taken, you want rate from us, that
word, make that question, you
can make anything, you break up,
where do you eat, because
which bank do you have, I make it, one
Sanjeev Road or vehicle, this to-do road, two men were
found,
if the answer to this is given in the front, this
year rota monitor, one mind happiness was found, give
questions to ask  Mark to answer
one mark husband died such and Chinese and Kunwar
and Tirv 64 two west 2006 very simple
third part so go through this also you will be
given one in it and from this you have to
make a request, that is if Baghwa then
must subscribe the channel or why not
appoint
that there will be two such pictures 2 F 2
request 269 636 introduction
kill the spelling and number question 26
do it 15 times out of 2015 there is no problem
and after that we will come to them some Raipur
means what to write but here you have to write
very little first of all you have to fill the religion form
very simple that if you think of any virus,
if it is unnecessary for the first time in any village then
what will you have to do first of all you will have to
fill the form of bus, airport or hotel,
they make you practice for it, so what happens, it is
generally difficult that it is your friend, she is going to
many, she is your friend, she is going with her husband and two children, so give
two days  She is going to stay in the hotel for a day,
they need one room, they need two rooms, it will be something like this, there will be only
four lines
and on that you have to fill in the blanks, how many of
us, how many
children, how many days are we going to stay, when are we going to come,
etc., it is
very simple, if your best is
clear from the previous competition, then these five marks are
absolutely free, you have to look at the top and
write down, that is why societies sleep,
what happens in them is that you have to write this letter,
but writing an active letter has a little
exaggeration, nothing, you have written a letter, what does it
mean to write 20 to 30 words, so twenty
to thirty words, means how many will be there, four or five
sentences, friend, it is easy and to make it easy,
they have given you three questions, these are three points,
write one or two sentences on each point, write one or two grammatically and
logically correct sentences, that's three
points, each point has three marks 3239
and only what we write for in the informal letter,
you write respect cancer
and written below in it, while
writing in the informal letter  Dear what ever and you
write below that front etc.
for that there is a route
that print two three plus 110 age very
simple example see how many things happen what happens is that
you are going to update
and write a letter on tourist information
what letter people in the beginning people are
arrested sir madam whatever it is and then they will
say my name the first point
see why you are taking the second point is that
it is about theatre music concert
and thirdly fun attraction so firstly what will you
say my name is Siddharth Jadhav I am
going to address after that I want to
address all these hotels etc decorate I want to
see museum or this but channel
thanks will you help me a little
and thirdly you will say I want to stay in a hotel will you
give me hotel attention that all this is
taken 10 marks
very simple so this is how to understand 15 Mother's
Day Shravan you say
such a big 15 route you are
writing only four or five sentences from your mind clear
and now we will come to an important part
This is called run meaning Sunnah so pay a
little attention to it because you
know what the problem is whether it is vaan vaan
or seat concept
that they will tell you something and you have to
write this answer but many people
face this problem especially after life
because especially if you are not in Germany then
you listen to German a lot so it is
important that you should
hear what they say. Now the questions should be simple, if the
questions are for children then you should understand only then
for example see how it happens that you are
given three options it is written
what is the roll number of Ghar Snyder and the
conversation is from can you tell me
where can I find Hair Splendor
Harsh name Rau Ras Na here on the second floor room
number 254 so if you know how to say 254 then it seems very easy the
answer will be like this that the
bag will
come on platform number 19 instead of train number 17 platform number 18 but
in one option there will be all three 17 18 19 so if
you did not understand anything that
What is the meaning then never think that 2017 is the
session for listening, you are understanding
rupees, practice of listening is very easy
and simple, first 616, what is the six and from that
15, what is the total of the last part
1111, those are told to you twice, they are
told twice so that you
can understand the first time what you are saying, you
can write the answer the second time, they are told twice, there are
3 options, there are only 3 options,
only 10 with the middle, those who were with the middle,
they are
told only once and then you are left with only two options,
it or fruit, what is the most important thing,
when this is the laser and we both will have our tests,
then definitely take your urine test, you do
not have to write anything there,
you are only considering this as objective, it is
not that you write what you tell, I
just pay attention to this while listening, you have to
write like this, so this objective is like this,
I said 11 things will be told twice,
four things once
Questions will come, you have to write on the said section, it is
simple
and Lance Klusener, which is my favorite
time, from seven to the end, that here
your test means this real-time test,
now the cost of such a competition is that good,
but there you can enjoy,
how does it happen to solve it, let's see,
what happens for the first 5 minutes, normal, which we do till now, now if
you were given a tub paragraph, then there are
small questions on it, which
we have done before - if you are given very
simple questions on it, it was for 5 minutes, the
second and third time are very
interesting, what happens in less time is
that you are given something to do and there are
two advertisements, there are two options,
for example, if you want to learn German, then
two options are given, what is this, German
Bakery, we have all the German food items available here
and in the middle European Language School, all these
European dishes are taught,
so where will you go, German Bakery  No, if you
go to a European language school,
what would be the problem? People would then look at German and
answer. It doesn't do that. For
example, if you look above, then Fragnet 1.5 is about to rain
and that in the first place there
is Regnan, but what is that, it is an open air phone shirt, if it
rains, there will be drops inside,
what is it in the second, waiter waiter, Haider Tima, so
if you understand it, then do it immediately. The important
thing is that this is the literal translation of the movement,
not a test on the partner or on the page, you have to
understand the list of words in a comprehensive
test. You don't need to understand all the words,
but you will get these ones with which you
can write the answer. Don't worry about that,
you don't need to understand all the words. If you
understand some important ones, then you
can write the answer. These five markets,
third, are even more interesting. Now
if you are kept in your Germany, then
you will have to understand the board,
rate, for this, this is the test, plastic
example, my favorite, now look at the post office, the
post went outside  If you look at the office,
when is your tense, it is Monday to morning and evening, on
Saturday only in the morning, so if you
go there on Saturday and say that I want to buy brief and
what is fabric cotton, tomato, on Saturday
you want to buy something by post, will you be
able to buy it, if you do not want to buy it in the evening, it is
not verified, then what will be the answer,
you do
n't need to know about the torch, it is very
magical, it is fun, it means it will be written like this that smoking is
prohibited here
and it will be written below that
you can smoke this cigarette,
25 Sir, what will happen to the file police, what should you
know, it is
called voting, you should know if the
basic payment is clear, then there is interest in this thing, so
see, as I said,
what was for five times and on a graph,
answer on afternoon graph, 5 March 22, 2012,
take 10 minutes and what is for 5 March, you will get
a board written, right from the board,
clear light, it is very simple, so if you
see  So it is so simple, see if your
German is good, Yagya Cube, understand
German well, then what is it, in the palace, ask your
questions, ask requests,
give your introduction, in the second, fill a small
form, write four or five sentences,
in the third, you heard something, take 15015 things
according to 15 years and in that, choose one of the
two answers on a small two bar graph
and write the answer on the board, there is
no height, Sanjay etc. We know that it is a
bit of an exam, let me
clarify the meaning of questions, people ask
questions among themselves, so the first
question is that brother, now dialer tune
into B1 B2, you cannot do that immediately,
yes you can go to any exam
directory externally and see it, it is not like that there is
already ODI or A, still and
what we talked about today, all the starting
route, its two papers, two papers, you will
get them on the page for the official exam itself, in exam preparation, you will get two
papers along with its contribution, so
if you did so much  So it is important to understand the format of the exam if you have
solved 156 papers then
nothing happens from that or from ads so it is important to
understand the format everything is about
how they give the exam so whatever
your early seat is
you can search there and ask thank you
sir you can go to the website and there
you will see
when the exam is and
how to apply for it it is different everywhere
it all varies at some places at some places you just have to send an email at
some specific
time at some places you have to log in there it
depends on every city at every place how many days the exam will be of this you vary so as much as
I know I
think right now in India in Pune the exam is
running for 60000 something and the upper age limit and the
acting chairman is 120 euros on it you
can check by wheat website you will get all the
information point that
it is for everyone so let's
come to PM a little state of
it  How can you get good marks?
Okay, so the first and simplest tip is that I
believe in the principle that if you know German
well and the concepts are clear,
then there is no need to do anything special for the exam.
Then it is as simple as iron.
If you can speak German well, if you can
listen to German well, if
you have the habit of studying German for hours, then you wo
n't have to do anything. You understand, so
what can you do for that? First of all, you should
improve your vocabulary a little.
For that, I
gave you Dongri Dissolve once and then
as we continued learning, we made these mentality
question sheets our own. We have already decided to solve two word
sheets. In total, you know
400 words so far. Along with that, if you
need any specific word, you
can use a dictionary. I use any dictionary.
You can use any.
Why not learn board? The second
important thing is that listening to German is very
important. What is the biggest problem?
People say that I have read so many
worlds but still I lose any urine, so
after liking and sharing this I
practiced football for a month but I do
n't know cricket,
from Mix Android if you want to learn cricket then you will have to
practice cricket,
similarly if you want to do well in it then you will have to
paint, so
what can you do for that, so what helps me
even while doing my desk job is this German
government channel adventure live
in German, it keeps running like Aaj Tak,
they have news on every topic,
but if you think that
what can that little news network do for you, then
catch any cartoon of Aaj Tak, break any one reason and
watch that cartoon in German, I
myself watch Paper Pick because I like it
very much that it will progress and become, I
mean one day they will show you stars, one day they will
tell you all the next points about doctors, so what will they do, they will say 50 bulwarks
and someone must be coloring like this, so
Malan means drawing, you will remember it with joy, in the
dark, take any of your cartoons,
listen to Jagmohan on any show,
flashlights, this is the most  It is important,
after that what is important is consistency,
like I said 5 sentences every day, if you
go and watch my first video again, then the
most important thing is that you make 5 sentences every day, you
just learn the concept, so on the
first day if you have not done that then do this chapati,
when you see the mode of return then do this
chapati from this, when you see the future tense then
set this chapati of this bell, where question see the question, make request,
then
make request, past tense if past tense were, then
how to make sentence, if
you do 5 sentences every day then you will not have to do anything different,
you just keep learning five new words,
you will become Vipin in five days, so
I hope that you all have understood the
example structure of German that Azam saw, the
tips that I have given you are to be
consistent,
you do not need to do anything more than 5 sentences, that is
if your  If you have any doubts then
write it in the comment section below, as I
said I am going to come live on Wednesday at 9:30 PM India Time,
I will
try my best to discuss it in that, I hope
you liked this episode, we will meet
in the next episode, thank you.